<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Elements xmlns="http://schemas.microsoft.com/sharepoint/">
  
  <ListInstance 
    Title="Announcements"
    OnQuickLaunch="TRUE"
    TemplateType="10000"
    Url="Lists/Announcements"
    Description="A announcements list with client-side rendering">

    <Data>
      <Rows>
        <Row>
          <Field Name="Title">Microsoft Releases SkyDrive App For Xbox 360</Field>
          <Field Name="Body">Microsoft today announced the release of SkyDrive app for Xbox 360 gaming console. This new app will allow you to enjoy the photos and video you upload on SkyDrive from web or apps through Xbox 360.</Field>
          <Field Name="Expires">01/01/2014</Field>
        </Row>
        <Row>
          <Field Name="Title">Microsoft Surface tablet arrives at Best Buy today</Field>
          <Field Name="Body">Microsoft's Surface  will be available for sale at Best Buy's Web site today starting at 2 p.m. PT. The device will then make it way to Best Buy retail outlets and select Best Buy Mobile stores this Sunday, December 16.</Field>
          <Field Name="Expires">07/15/2014</Field>
        </Row>
        <Row>
          <Field Name="Title">Microsoft Expands Distribution for Microsoft Surface</Field>
          <Field Name="Body"> Microsoft Corp. today announced plans to make Microsoft Surface available at additional retailers as soon as mid-December. In addition, the company announced the extension of the Microsoft holiday stores, including the transition of several of the stores into permanent Microsoft retail outlets.</Field>
          <Field Name="Expires">07/15/2014</Field>
        </Row>
        <Row>
          <Field Name="Title">Microsoft Surface tablets announced, powered by Windows 8</Field>
          <Field Name="Body">After days of speculation and rumors, Microsoft's major announcement has just been unveiled at a press event in Los Angeles: a Surface tablet. We suspected the company might be working on its own tablet, and Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer revealed the device on stage at Milk Studios in Los Angeles today.</Field>
          <Field Name="Expires">07/15/2014</Field>
        </Row>
      </Rows>
    </Data>
    
  </ListInstance>
</Elements>
