<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../buildx/script2/preview.xslt"?>
<gallery_sample xmlns="http://microsoft.com/wdcml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://microsoft.com/wdcml ../../buildx/schema/xsd/wdcml.xsd">
  <metadata id="gallery_samples.96_gallery" type="gallery_sample" msdnID="99bba396-3b4b-4520-9367-f9b87772c6b3">
    <title>Sensors HID Driver Sample</title>
    <devlang value="cpp"/>
    <tech value="gallery_samples"/>
    <index/>
    <sample_langs>
      <sample_lang xml:lang="en-us"/>
    </sample_langs>
  </metadata>
  <content>
    <desc>
      <p>
        <abstract>The sample HID driver for sensors demonstrates how an OEM or IHV could write a UMDF driver to support sensors that are compliant with the HID Sensor Class Driver specification. This driver is also helpful for IHVs who must design and test firmware for a HID-based sensor. This sample driver is identical to the HID class driver that will ship in-box for Windows Developer Preview.</abstract>
      </p>
      <p>This sample driver is generally identical the HID Sensor Class Driver that is available in <tla rid="win_8_client"/> and provides developers with the following:</p>
      <list>
        <item>Source code to help build and compile a working driver for <tla rid="win_7_client"/>.</item>
        <item>Source code to help debug the hardware/firmware during development.</item>
      </list>
      <p>There are three instances where you may need to modify the sample driver.</p>
      <proch>
        <item>The sample does not support your sensor.</item>
        <item>The sample supports your sensor; but, it does not support unique functionality on your particular device. </item>
        <item>The sample needs to run on an earlier version of Windows.</item>
      </proch>
      <p>The sample driver is based on the HID protocol. It supports the <xref rid="sensors.the_driver_file_list" targtype="ovw">eighteen common sensors</xref>. In addition, it supports a Custom class that lets you integrate any HID sensor not found in this list.

</p>
      <p>For a complete description of this sample and its underlying code and functionality, refer to the <xref rid="sensors.sensors_hid_driver_sample" targtype="ovw">Sensors HID driver sample</xref> description in the Windows Driver Kit documentation.</p>
    </desc>
    <outline/>
    <license_info>
      <default_license/>
    </license_info>
    <programming_models>
      <programming_model value="win32"/>
    </programming_models>
    <application_frameworks>
    </application_frameworks>
    <driver_models>
      <driver_model value="UMDF"/>
    </driver_models>
    <driver_techs>
      <driver_tech value="Sensors and Location"/>
      <driver_tech value="Windows Driver"/>
    </driver_techs>
    <related_techs>
    </related_techs>
    <os_requirements>
      <min_os>
        <client name="win8"/>
        <server name="none"/>
      </min_os>
    </os_requirements>
    <required_sdks>
      <min_sdk>
        <tla rid="windows_driver_kit"/>
      </min_sdk>
    </required_sdks>
    <supported_ides>
      <supported_ide>
        <tla rid="vs11_pro"/>
      </supported_ide>
      <supported_ide>
        <tla rid="vs11_ultimate"/>
      </supported_ide>
    </supported_ides>
    <build_info>
      <authored_instructions>
        <section>
          <sectioncontents>
            <proch>
              <item>Start the <tla rid="tla_visualstu2011"/> development environment.</item>
              <item>Select the build configuration (for example, Windows Developer Preview Debug) and the architecture (for example Win32).</item>
              <item>From the File/Open/Project/Solution… menu, navigate to the VcxProj or sln file and load the project</item>
              <item>From the Build menu, select Build Solution.</item>
            </proch>
            <p>If the build succeeds, you will find the driver DLL and INF files in a subdirectory of your project directory. For example, if you built the  Debug configuration and Win32 architecture, the DLL and INF files will be placed in projectDirectory\WindowsDeveloperPreviewDebug\x86 directory.</p>
          </sectioncontents>
        </section>
      </authored_instructions>
    </build_info>
    <run_info>
      <authored_instructions>
        <section>
          <title>Installing the sample</title>
          <sectioncontents>
            <p>To install the sensors driver sample:</p>
            <proch>
              <item>Ensure that the driver builds without errors.</item>
              <item>Enable test signing by running the command “bcdedit /set testsigning on” from an elevated command prompt. (You’ll need to reboot your machine after you enable test signing.)</item><item>Copy the DLL and INF files to a separate folder</item>
              <item>Install a HID sensor board with a VID = C1CA and PID = 0020. Locate this newly installed board in the Device Manager under Human Interface Devices – it will be a “HID-compliant device.”</item>
              <item>Right-click on the device and select “Update Driver Software…"
</item>
              <item>Select “Browse my computer for driver software”</item>
              <item>Select “Let me pick from a list of device drivers on my computer”</item>
              <item>Select “Have disk…”</item>
              <item>Select “Browse…”</item>
              <item>Navigate to the folder in which the DLL and INF files were placed in step 2. Select the INF and select “Open”</item>
              <item>Select OK</item>
              <item>Select Next</item>
              <item>If a Windows security prompt appears, select “Install this driver software anyway”</item>
              <item>The device will appear in Device Manager under Sensors as a “HID Sensor Collection.”</item>
            </proch>
          </sectioncontents>
        </section>
      </authored_instructions>
    </run_info>
    <seealso>
      <xref rid="sensors.sensor_driver_design_guide" targtype="ovw">Sensors Design Guide</xref>
      <xref targtype="ovw" rid="sensors.programming_guide">Sensors Programming Guide</xref>
    </seealso>
  </content>
  <feature_teams>
    <feature_team_info comp_central_path="" dev_owner="gparks" writer_owner="donnm"/>
  </feature_teams>
  <workflow_control_host/>
</gallery_sample>
